<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Virtual Atoms Lab</title>
    <link>https://virtualatoms.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Virtual Atoms Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://virtualatoms.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Codes</title>
      <link>https://virtualatoms.org/codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://virtualatoms.org/codes/</guid>
      <description>Our group actively develops and contributes to open-source software. Much of the software we develop is designed to help manage, analyse, and intepret first-principles calculations. Some of the codes we develop and maintain are listed below. More information can be found on our GitHub page.
amset An efficient framework for calculating electron scattering rates from first principles. Code | Paper
atomate2 Computational workflows for high-throughput materials science. Code
IFermi Tools for the generation, analysis and visualisation of Fermi surfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us</title>
      <link>https://virtualatoms.org/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://virtualatoms.org/join/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re hiring! We have positions available. Please get in touch with Alex by email for more details.
UROP position for summer 2024 A funded summer project is available for Imperial undergraduates. Interested applicants should send their CV and a paragraph on their research interests to Dr. Ganose before 29th November 2023.
PhD Scholarships Funding is available through a number of scholarships including:
Imperial Marshall Scholarship Scheme Imperial Chemistry DTP Scheme China Scholarship Council (CSC) Scheme Post-doctoral fellowships Support is available for postdoctoral fellowship applications, including Royal Commission for the Exhibition of 1851 fellowships, Marie Sklodowska-Curie Fellowships and the Royal Society&amp;rsquo;s Newton International Fellowship scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://virtualatoms.org/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://virtualatoms.org/papers/</guid>
      <description>Preprints &amp;ldquo;The temperature-dependence of carrier mobility is not a reliable indicator of the dominant scattering mechanism&amp;rdquo; arXiv:2210.01746
&amp;ldquo;Learned Force Fields Are Ready For Ground State Catalyst Discovery&amp;rdquo; arXiv:2209.12466
&amp;ldquo;Crystal Toolkit: A Web App Framework to Improve Usability and Accessibility of Materials Science Research Algorithms&amp;rdquo; arXiv:2302.06147
&amp;ldquo;Atomate2: Modular workflows for materials science&amp;rdquo; 10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-tcr5h
2025 &amp;ldquo;Cross-disciplinary perspectives on the potential for artificial intelligence across chemistry&amp;rdquo; Chemical Society Reviews (2025)
&amp;ldquo;Advances in theory and computational methods for next-generation thermoelectric materials&amp;rdquo; Applied Physics Reviews (2025)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://virtualatoms.org/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://virtualatoms.org/research/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Virtual Atoms Lab research group run by Dr Alex Ganose at Imperial College London. We use computational materials chemistry, data-driven approaches, and machine learning to discover new functional materials for photovoltaics, thermoelectrics, and more. We develop a suite of open-source codes to help tackle these challenges. See the codes page for more details.
We are members of the Institute for Digital Molecular Design and Fabrication (DigiFAB), the Thomas Young Centre (TYC) for Materials Modelling, the Centre for Plastic Electronics (CPE), the Artificial Intelligence Network, and the Materials Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://virtualatoms.org/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 22:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://virtualatoms.org/team/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Alex Ganose Lecturer, Imperial College London Co-investigator, Materials Project
Website | Scholar | GitHub
Alex Ganose is a Lecturer in the Department of Chemistry at Imperial College London.
His research uses computational materials chemistry, machine learning, and data science to design new materials for pressing problems, including renewable energy generation (photovoltaics &amp;amp; thermoelectrics) and energy storage.
Alex was awarded his EngD in chemistry from University College London in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
